I know that's not catchy at all but
hopefully you'll remember that
title uh by the time we finished the
sermon today but the first Thanksgiving
Thanksgiving is a time where we come
together as
family and um we just Celebrate life
amen we sit around the table we eat
together and we fellowship and so it's a
very special
time and today I want to talk to you
about the first Thanksgiving let's pray
Heavenly
Father guide
us as we open your
word this is our prayer in jesus' name
amen the event that Americans commonly
call the first Thanksgiving was
celebrated by pilgrims after their first
harvest in the New World
on October 16 on October
1621 Thanksgiving became a Federal
holiday as you heard a little bit
earlier in 1863 during the American
Civil War Lincoln proclaimed a national
day of Thanksgiving and praise to our
benefit to Our beneficient Father who
dwelleth in the
Heavens to be celebrated on the fourth
Thursday of
November Thanksgiving it is a Time
that we get together and
celebrate really the things that God has
done for
us but
today I'm not going to talk
about uh
Thanksgiving as we celebrate it but I'm
actually going to talk about Jesus
Thanksgiving because
just as we give
thanks um for the things that God has
done we're going to look
today at Jesus's own
Thanksgiving and to do that we're going
to actually take a journey we're going
to go and I invite you actually to turn
with me to the book of First
Corinthians chapter
11 1
Corinthians chapter 11
1 Corinthians 11: 24 and
25 when you get there please say
Amen we'll start with verse
23 Paul here was speaking he says for I
have received of the Lord that which
also I delivered unto
you that the Lord Jesus the same night
in which he was betrayed took bread
and when he had given what thanks he
Breo it and said take eat this is my
body which is broken for you this do in
remembrance of
me after the same manner also he took
the cup when he had SED saying this cup
is the New Testament in my blood this do
ye as often as you drink it in
remembrance of me for as often as you
eat of the bread and drink of this cup
you do show the Lord's death till he
come
Jesus gave thanks at the Last Supper it
was to be his last supper in this
world why does
Jesus give thanks over the bread and
over the wine
well let me ask you a
question why do we give
thanks how many of you have ever given
thanks to God okay and why did you give
thanks to
him
because I just want you to think of
think of a certain time that you thanked
God you were just like thank you God why
did you thank him
okay because he
answered prayer or because
he he provided or he came through right
and so we celebrated thank you God and
that's typically how we how we approach
thanking God but I want you to notice
something here and it may not really
stick out to you you may be like well
you know that that doesn't really stick
out to me that well but I want you to
see here
that Jesus gave thanks over the bread
and over the wine before he offered
it he gave thanks in
advance now again it might seem like not
a big deal because you know when we eat
our meals what do we do we give thanks
in advance and what are we thanking God
for we're thanking for the meal he has
provided but I want to suggest to you
that Jesus was not thanking God for
providing Bread and
Wine listen carefully when we go to to a
meal and we we pray and even at
Thanksgiving when we thank God for the
food we are thanking him because of the
food that is there on the table that we
say he has what he's provided is that
correct yeah we're thanking God for
something he has already done he's
provided and therefore we thank him for
something he's already done but I I want
to suggest to you that when Jesus was
thanking God he was thanking him in
advance
okay in order for us to understand this
we're going to go to several other
places in the scripture where Jesus gave
thanks in
advance so come with me
we're going to go over to the Book of
Matthew chapter 15 Matthew chapter 15
and as we we begin to look at these
these several P places there's three of
them all together two of them we're
going to merge together because they're
really describing a very similar
event Matthew chapter
15 and let's begin with verse 29
the Bible says there and Jesus departed
from then and came nigh unto the Sea of
Galilee and went up into a mountain and
sat down there and great multitudes came
unto him having with them those who were
lame blind dumb
maimed and many many
others and cast them down at jesus' feet
and he healed them in so much that the
multitude wondered when they saw the
dumb to speak the m to Behold The Lame
to walk and the blind to see and they
did what glorified the god of
Israel then Jesus called his disciples
unto him and said I have compassion on
the multitude because they continue with
me now how long days 3 days and have
nothing to eat and I will not send them
away fasting lest they faint in the way
and his disciples say unto him when
should we have uh have so much bread in
the wilderness as to fill so great a
what all right so what's going on
here Jesus has just finished healing and
he's healing all manner of people and
the people are glorifying him as the Son
of God and then the Bible says that that
it's this great multitude this is what
everyone great multitude that is
hungering and how long have they been
with him days 3 days how long
everyone 3 days okay so let me ask this
just in case you didn't hear me how long
everyone three days they've been with
him three days and he says all right
they have been with me three days and
they are hungry and I'm not going to let
them starve I'm going to feed
them after how long days 3
days the Bible tells us in verse 32 33
Jesus said unto them how many
loaves have ye and they said seven and a
few little
fish and he commanded the multitude to
sit down on the ground and he took the
seven Loaves and the fishes and what did
he do he no no no no no no what did he
do he gave thanks okay pause for a
second what is Jesus giving thanks for
yeah I think what what is he what is he
giving thanks
for is he giving thanks for the bread
and the
fish what is he thanking God for who's
he giving thanks to God what is he
giving thanks
for okay you all are like well I don't
know what he's giving God thanks for I
need you to think carefully with
me let's say that you and I were there
you know now we're not Jesus but we're
there and oh everybody's hungry and
we're thinking to ourselves well you
know what I think that God can provide
bread but man to feed all this people
that's going to take a what a miracle so
what would you do all right everyone's
looking at you right hey aren't you the
guy that's really connected with God
yeah yeah so they're looking at you and
what do you think they're
expecting a miracle right so what do you
do what do you do you
what you pray how many of you pray let
me see your hands you're in a situation
you're going to pray and what's your
prayer going to
be you're going to do what ask right so
you're going to ask God lord can you God
can you turn this
little amount of food that we have into
a lot of food and then if it happens
then what do you
do you thank
him is that right you you you ask first
okay Lord there's a lot of people here
and we need food so what we do is we say
dear Lord please please please we need a
miracle right now can you provide this
food can you multiply
this bread these fish so that the people
can eat but Jesus doesn't do
that what does he
do he thanks God in
advance because he knows what's coming
he has faith in the word of God are you
with me so Jesus does not ask and then
say thank you afterward thank you Lord
thank you Father for coming through this
miracle no no no the Bible says he thank
him in
advance and and when he thanked
him verse verse 30 36 he took the seven
Loaves and the fish and gave thanks and
braak them and gave them to his
disciples and the disciples to the
multitude and they did all eat and were
filled and they took up of the broken
meat that was left seven baskets
full seven basket
full
three days listen carefully to me guys
it was after three
days that Jesus
provided
bread for a great
multitude and I want you to understand
that this miracle was glorified the Son
of God there was a lesson that Jesus was
trying to give that Jesus was trying to
illustrate and I believe down to this
very day because you see Jesus himself
said I am the bread of
life and listen to
me the bread of life was broken for us
and remained in the Tomb for how long 3
days and at the end end of those three
days when Jesus Christ came back to life
in essence he his death burial and
Resurrection would provide meat are you
with me for a great
multitude for all who would come after
him this
miracle Jesus giving thanks in
advance was foreshadowing the very fact
that his death burial and Resurrection
would provide
bread for the
world Jesus gave thanks in
advance because he
knew what his own death burial and
Resurrection would bring to mankind if
you're with me so far just let me hear
you say
Amen now we're going to
go to the next place in the scriptures
where Jesus gives thanks by the way I
said three places this was one the other
one was right before it in Matthew 14
where Jesus feeds uh the 5,000 and there
were 12 loaves of 12 baskets left over
and that's very interesting in one
there's 12 baskets left over in the
other there is seven that's very
interesting because if you think about
it 12 baskets almost as if he was saying
one for each
disciple My
Sacrifice is going to provide enough for
God's Church
Israel the 12 tribes spiritually
speaking to feed the entire
world Take My Sacrifice into the world
preach the gospel bring them the bread
of life
in the Book of
Revelation there are seven churches
those seven churches represent the
church in all its stages from the first
coming of Christ down to the second
coming of Christ so in both of these
examples you have enough left over one
for Israel the 12 tribes spiritual
Israel one for the seven churches which
is a different way of talking about the
same group of people God's people
throughout from the time of his death
bual and Resurrection all the way to the
second coming of Christ in other words
Beloved the sacrifice of Christ provides
the world with bread so that they may
eat and he says to his people take this
bread take these baskets of bread and
Feed the World Jesus thanked God for
something he knew was
coming he thanked him in advance now
come again with me to m to the Book of
John
John 11 now some of you may already know
where this is going because this is the
other time that Jesus thanked God in
advance John
11 John
11 beginning with verse
one John 11
verse1 the Bible says now a certain man
was sick named who Lazarus of Bethany
the town of Mary and her sister Martha
and it was that Mary was anointed it was
that Mary which was anoint which
anointed the Lord with ointment and
wiped his feet with her hair whose
brother Lazarus was sick therefore his
sister sent unto him saying Lord behold
he whom thou lovest is
sick when Jesus heard that he said this
sickness is not unto death but for what
the glory
of the of God that the Son of God might
be what glorified thereby so how many of
you know what's coming here what's
coming Lazarus dies and Jesus is going
to do what resurrect him and Jesus says
that what's about to happen is
specifically to glorify the Son of
God now I know what you're thinking how
was the son of God
glorified because what
because he raised
Lazarus from the dead right all right
watch this guys come come follow me here
verse 5 John
11:5 now Jesus loved Martha and her
sister and
Lazarus when he heard therefore that he
was sick he immediately
went that's how it should read
guys come on like okay you hear someone
sick now now you this is the narrative
and because you heard that he was sick
what do you expect to come
next you immediately you what he said
and you immediately go wait you love
that person so when you heard they were
sick what do you
do you immediately
go the text doesn't say that does
it it's kind of crazy how it's written
now Jesus loved Lazarus therefore when
he heard he was sick he
waited like that doesn't make
sense but the Bible says here verse 5 uh
uh um or verse six when he heard
therefore that he was sick he Abode how
many days two days still in the same
place where he was then after that pause
for a second after that so what would
after that
mean yeah after the two days which would
mean what day was
that okay so on the third day so in case
you didn't hear what I just said on the
third
day case you didn't hear what I just
said let me say one more time on the
third day Jesus leaves to go raise
Lazarus so the Bible tells us that when
he gets to to Bethany
uh that they say that Lazarus has been
dead how long he's been dead now 4 days
notice with me verse 14 John
11:14 then said Jesus unto them plainly
Lazarus is dead and I glad for your
sakes that I was not there to the intent
that you may what believe nevertheless
let us go on to him now who's he talking
to
here the disciples hold on wait a minute
it that you may believe let me ask a
question do the disciples believe that
Jesus is the Messiah at this
time okay they've just left everything
and they're following him around and
they don't believe that he's the
Messiah no the disciples what they
believed he was a messiah so why is
Jesus speaking to the disciples saying
what's about to happen is so that you
will believe
why in the world is he saying
that
okay check this out come come so jump
down with me to verse verse 17 the Bible
says
now when Jesus came he found that he had
lay in the grave for 4 days come down
with me to verse 2 23 Jesus said unto
her thy brother shall rise again Martha
said unto him I know that he shall rise
again in the resurrection at the last
day Jesus said unto her I am am what the
resurrection and the life he that
believeth in me though he were dead yet
he shall live and whosoever liveth and
believeth in me shall never die
believeth thou
this she said unto him yes yes Lord I
believe that thou art the Christ the son
of God which should come into the world
now jump down with me to verse
38 verse
38 Jesus therefore again groaning in
himself cometh to the Grave it was a
cave and a Stone lay upon
it Jesus said take you away the stone
Martha the sister of him that was dead
saith unto him Lord by this time he
stinketh for he's been dead four days
Jesus said unto her said I not unto thee
that if thou would believe thou should
see the glory of God then they took away
the Stone from the place where he where
the dead was laid and Jesus lifted up
his eyes and said
father please
raise Lazarus from the
dead what does the text
say father I what I thank thee that thou
Hast heard
me okay hold on a second how do you
thank God that he has heard you if you
have not the the the account does not
say and he
prayed when do you usually thank God
you usually thank God
after he's done something for you after
he's come
through Jesus says here father I thank
you that you heard me you heard me what
is he thanking him
for what's about to
happen Lazarus is about to be raised
from the dead now if that were you and
I and we were someone's looking at you
like can you pray and see if God will
what are you going to
do you're going to pray Lord please can
you raise this man from the we're not
going to thank God in
advance because we're worried about will
will this
happen Jesus thanks God in
advance for the raising of
Lazarus notice with me verse 39 verse
I'm sorry verse verse
41 he says there to the latter part
father I thank thee that thou Hast heard
me and I knew thou hearest me always but
because of the people that would stand
by I said it that they may believe that
thou Hast what sent me hold on and when
they had thus spoken he cried with a
loud voice Lazarus come forth
and he that was dead came forth bound
hand and foot with grave clothes and his
face was bound about with a napkin Jesus
said unto them loose him and let him
go okay what did Jesus prayes now what
did he just
say he
said wait wait wait he
said I knew that thou hearest me always
but because of the people which which
stand by I said that they may believe
that thou Hast what sent me okay what
does he mean sent
me what is he talking about sent
me in this context what are he what is
he saying when he says you sent
me all right remember Jesus hears that
Lazarus is is dead and then because
because he loved him
he he
waits well what's he waiting
for he's waiting to be what he's waiting
to be
sent you guys he's waiting to be
sent the glory of God Jesus does not say
look the raising of Lazarus from the
dead that's not what I want you to
see what I want you to see is the fact
that I was sent by my
father now I did not come on the first
day I did not come on the second
day I
came I left I began my journey to come
forth to raise the dead on the third
day I need you to
see that the reason that I waited 3 days
before coming forth I don't know if you
before coming forth to raise a dead is
because it was given me of my
father and beloved what I'm saying to
you today is
this Lazarus
himself was a
symbol of Jesus Christ
Lazarus being dead in the Tomb with a
stone rolled over it with a napkin you
remember when they went to to Jesus's
grave and they saw the
napkin and the stone had been rolled
away Jesus had been loosed and let
go the reason why Jesus Waits 3 days yes
Lazarus is raised on the fourth day but
Jesus Goes Forth to raise him on the
third day Jesus was foreshadowing his
own death and so this is why he thanked
God in advance because this miracle of
Lazarus was to point forward to his
own death burial and Resurrection the
feeding of the multitude he thanked him
in advance because that feeding of the
multitude was to point forward to the
results of his death burial and
Resurrection now
now now that we got that let's go back
to Jesus's
Thanksgiving
dinner did you catch what I just
said what was Jesus's Thanksgiving
dinner it was the last the last supper
come with me Matthew chapter 26 and you
need to check this out Matthew chapter
26 Matthew 26 and verse 2
6 Matthew 26 and verse
26 the Bible says here Matthew
verse
26 and as they were eating Jesus Took
bread and blessed it and break it and
gave it to the disciples and said take
eat this is my body and he took the cup
and gave thanks and gave it to them
saying drink ye all of it for this is my
blood of the new testament which is shed
for many for the remission of sins pause
for a
second 1 Corinthians it tells us that he
gave
thanks over the bread and here it says
he gave thanks over the wine here's my
question for
you is Jesus giving thanks for the bread
and the wine that is before him is he
saying thank you God for bring bringing
bread to the table and wine is that what
he's saying when we pray over our food
we're praying thank you Lord for
providing this food that's what we're
praying thank you Lord for bringing this
food to the table when Jesus prayed when
Jesus was giving thanks over the bread I
suggest to you that he was giving thanks
in advance
you see beloved he was giving
thanks in
advance for his
own death burial and
resurrection that would
provide food for me and
you I want you to think about that for a
second how is Jesus thanking his father
for his own
sacrifice thank you
Father I thank you in
advance for this Plan of
Salvation that will
save my
people from their
sins guys think about that
Jesus at his
Thanksgiving was thanking his Heavenly
Father for
us how important must you
be how important must you
be that
Jesus thanks his father
for
us this
sacrifice Jesus thanking his father in
advance knowing that my death burial and
Resurrection my death burial and
Resurrection will provide food for the
world from now until I come
again you see Not only was Jesus
thanking the the father for for this
Plan of Salvation he was thanking the
father because his resurrection would
lead to the
resurrection of all of his
people thank you
Father that this sacrifice this bread
and this wine that is about to be broken
I thank you in advance for what it's
going to do because not only is it a
foreshadowing of my death burial and
resurrection and my being able to
provide meat and food for the whole
world but it is also a foreshadow of the
death burial and resurrection of all of
my
people
wait and it is also a
foreshadow of the fact that
they will
spend the first
Thanksgiving in
heaven wait wait wait in in the new
world
y in the what do we what what do we hear
about the pilgrims their Thanksgiving
was their celebration their first
celebration in the new world what we
call America the old world was Europe
the new world was America God is saying
to us listen to me you get to
spend Thanksgiving remember how Jesus
said I will not eat this again with you
you until we eat it a
new in the heavens made
new
beloved Jesus was thanking his father in
advance for the meal that we will all
eat together as a result of his death
burial and Resurrection
Jesus was thanking his Heavenly
Father for
us I thank
you for providing this
sacrifice that they may
live see beloved I want you to check
this out we're getting ready to close
this up but I need you to listen to
this Jesus is the Thanksgiving
lamb now I know we're used to
Thanksgiving
turkeys but Jesus is the Thanksgiving
lamb and when you think of that
Thanksgiving lamb it brings our mind
back
to the
fact that God himself had
prophesied that he would bring a lamb
how many remember the story of Abraham
sacrificing his only
son do you know what the Bible says the
Bible says that as Abraham is taking his
son to be sacrif
God told him the journey that you're
about to take it's about
[Music]
um three days
long on the third day the Bible says
Abraham lifted up his eyes and saw the
place where he was to sacrifice Isaac
now how many of you if you were Abraham
would have been thankful as the knife
was going down and you heard
stop thank you Lord
thank
you I want you to imagine the kind of
thank you that must have came from
Abraham's heart thank
you remember Abraham said God himself
will
provide a
lamb a
sacrifice well beloved that sacrifice
you know the story right Abraham turns
around and there's a ram caught in the
thicket right guess what that's not the
ram
that was not the ram that God was going
to provide yes it was a lamb that God
provided temporarily but the lamb he
would provide was his own
son and we ought to say thank you God
that that sacrifice was not
stopped because if it was where would we
all
be we would have nothing to be thankful
for
thank you
God for that
sacrifice when the children of Israel
were in
Egypt the Bible says that God told Moses
to tell the children of Israel that they
must take a lamb and sacrifice it
because he was going to lead them out of
Egypt into
the promised land that lamb was called
the pass over
lamb God had provided himself a lamb and
when you think of this story what was
happening with the children of Israel
they were leaving an old world to enter
into a new one beloved listen to me it
is by the sacrifice of our Thanksgiving
lamb that you and I will be able to sit
at the welcome table in heaven
and
celebrate the
first
Thanksgiving in a new
world what a
Thanksgiving that will
be beloved as you get together and
celebrate your thanksgivings and
and you know how Thanksgiving can be
sometimes sometimes you like your
family and sometimes you're like oh no
Thanksgiving
again but listen to me heaven will not
be like
that heaven will not be it will be the
best
Thanksgiving that we will ever
experience and we will celebrate amen we
will celebrate that Thanksgiving again
and again and again knowing that there
will be no more pain no more suffering
no more sorrow No More Tears no more
death
God we are going to celebrate with God
for all
eternity and so beloved my appeal is
this right now let's thank God in
advance I'm going to be there you're
going to be there thank you God in
advance for that first great
Thanksgiving celebration in heaven Doran
I'm going to invite you up
going to invite you up to
pray and beloved as we get together at
our various Thanksgiving celebrations
today I'm sorry uh this coming week I
want you to keep in
mind that there is coming a
grand
Thanksgiving let us all be there to
celebrate that first Thanksgiving